看来暴风雨已过  纽约客们
It looks like the storm has passed, New Yorkers.
昨夜十八厘米的降水量达到了本季度最高
A season-high seven inches of rain last night.
某些地区狂风大作  洪水泛滥
High winds and flooding in some areas...
甚至让有些纽约客滞留城中
even left some New Yorkers stranded.
政府人员今早还在抢修
City crews still working this morning.
他们正试图恢复市内几个地区的电力供应
They're trying to restore power to several areas in the boroughs.
好消息是  今天天气晴朗  最高气温十五度左右
Good news is, today should be sunny with highs in the low 60s...
天气反季节地温和
unseasonably mild...
在持续几周的恶劣天气之后  终于出现改观
a real change from the relentless weather of these past few weeks.
所以赶快出门  享受阳光  去公园逛逛
So get out there, enjoy the sun, go to the park,
能出门就别待在家
get outside if you can...
因为好天气可不会持续太久
because it's not gonna last long.
本周晚些时候将迎来冬季风暴
Winter storms are turning later in the week...
周末气温将会骤降
Making for a severe temperature drop over the weekend.
可能预示着今年漫长的冬季将提早到来
Could be signs for an early and potentially long winter.
你在干什么  约翰
What are you doing, John?
看你
Looking at you.
过来
Come here.
你还在拍吗
Are you still filming?
疾速追杀
又一年了
Just an anniversary.
好久不见
It's been a while.
请节哀
My condolences.
你还好吗
How are you holding up?
我不停地问  "为什么是她"
I keep asking, "Why her?"
世事本就无常
There's no rhyme or reason to this life.
今天这样的日子总是混在琐碎日常中
It's days like today scattered among the rest.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
别太自责
Don't blame yourself.
你来的真正目的是什么  马库斯
What are you really doing here, Marcus?
不过是看望老朋友而已
Just checkin' up on an old friend.
再见  约翰
Good bye, John.
-你是约翰·威克吗  -是的
- John Wick? - Yes.
请在这里签字
Sign here, please.
把笔还我
And the pen.
抱歉
Sorry.
-包裹收好  晚安  -谢谢
- Here you go. Good night. - Thanks.
凯芙琳快递
约翰  很抱歉我不能陪伴你
"John, I'm sorry l can't be there for you.
但你仍然需要去爱一些物  爱一些人
But you still need something, someone to love.
那就从爱它开始吧
So start with this.
因为爱车可不算数
Because the car doesn't count.
我爱你  约翰
I love you, John.
疾病的阴影已经笼罩了我们太久
This illness has loomed over us for a long time...
现在我已找到我的安宁  你也要找到你的
and now that I have found my peace, find yours.
直到那天  你最好的朋友  海伦
Until that day, your best friend, Helen."
黛西
Daisy.
当然是叫这个
Of course.
来吧
Come on.
我醒了  马上就起
I'm up. I'm up.
马上就起
I'm up.
对了
Right.
怎么了
What?
等会儿再去给你买狗粮
We'll grab you some kibble later.
是真的吗
Is this true?
车不错啊
Nice ride.
野马  Boss 429
Mustang. Boss 429.
她是70年的吗
She a '70?
这款车以前只在1969至1970年生产过
直到2018年才复刻  因此原版车极为稀有
69年的
'69.
-这车真的不错  -谢谢
- Beautiful car. - Thanks.
-开个价吧  -你说什么
- How much? - Excuse me?
开个价卖这辆车
How much for the car?
她不卖
She's not for sale.
我可喜欢狗了
I love dogs.
谁都有价码  贱人
这个贱人没有
这混蛋以为自己是谁
祝你愉快  先生
You have good day, sir.
好吧  那你上来吧
All right. Come on, then.
你好吗
How you doin'?
你要上厕所吗
You need to go?
该死的车钥匙在哪儿
让那条狗闭嘴
去把钥匙找来
在这里  我找到了
好好睡吧  贱人
这车我打算自己开  不卖了
奥雷利欧
Aurelio!
我要新的车辆识别码和干净的档案
I want a new VIN number and some clean papers.
你从哪搞来的这辆车
Where'd you get that car?
车在不在
Is it here?
之前在
It was.
-我问你到底从哪搞来的这辆车  -这很重要吗
- I asked you where the hell did you get it? - Who gives a shit?
约索夫·塔拉索夫干的
Iosef Tarasov nicked it.
维戈的儿子
Viggo's son.
是的
Yeah.
行了  滚出我的店  立刻滚出去
All right, get out of it. Get out of my shop. Get out right now.
你昏头了吗  奥雷利欧  你可是我们的小弟
Did you just lose your shit, Aurelio? Because we own you.
你刚刚说什么  你刚刚跟我说什么
What did you say? What did you say to me?
你是我们的小弟
We own you.
你算个屁  臭小子
You don't own me, punk.
我跟你父亲一起工作  懂吗
I work with your father. All right?
你们把车的主人杀了吗
The owner of that car, did you kill him or what?
没有
No.
但我们把他的狗弄死了
We sure as hell fucked up his dog.
弄死了他的狗  你们就干了这个
You fucked up his dog? That's what you did?
-你们把他的狗弄死了  -是啊
- You fucked up his dog? - Yeah.
真疯狂啊  伙计
That's crazy shit, man.
看看你  这下可好
Look at you. That's great.
你打算进我的店  还拿枪指着我的头
You're gonna come into my shop and you're gonna pull a gun on me.
你可真厉害  来
That's great, man. Come on.
要么你现在一枪把我崩了
Now, you kill me right now...
要么就他妈滚出我的店
or you get the fuck out of my shop.
维戈不会喜欢这样
Viggo is not gonna like this.
你怎么知道维戈的喜好
How do you know what Viggo likes or doesn't like?
我告诉你  他会理解的
I'll tell you somethin' he's gonna understand.
你还真有种啊  老东西
You've got a fuckin' pair on you, old man!
看来我们只能去别的地方处理这车了
I guess we'll be takin' our business someplace else.
你打算怎么办
So what are you gonna do?
我要辆车
I need a ride.
我是奥雷利欧
Aurelio speaking.
我听说你打了我儿子
I heard you struck my son.
-是的  先生  -我能问问为什么吗
- Yes, sir, I did. - And may I ask why?
行啊  因为你儿子偷了约翰·威克的车  先生
Yeah, well, because he stole John Wick's car, sir...
还杀了他的狗
and, killed his dog.
维戈
Viggo.
什么事
Yeah?
他们同意你的条款了
They've agreed to your terms.
虽然看上去你也没给他们多少选择  是吧
It's not like you gave them much of a choice anyway though, right?
祝贺你
Congratulations.
先生
Sir?
你看见我儿子了吗
Have you seen my son?
旅途如何  孩子
How was your trip, kid?
我们短时间内不会再有他们的消息了
We won't be hearing from them anytime soon.
或者永远不会
Or ever.
外套不错
That's a nice jacket.
-谢谢  -真的
- Thanks. - Yeah.
擦干净
要我离开吗
Should I go?
不用
Nyet
-维戈  说英语好吗  -我说别走  见鬼
- Viggo, English, please. Come on. - Stay, goddamn it!
我干什么了
What did I do?
你捅了个大篓子
我们按你要求的做了  没人看见
We did what you asked. No one saw shit.
我说的不是大西洋城那事
I'm not talking about Atlantic City.
那是什么事
What then?
你说的是奥雷利欧那事
You mean Aurelio's?
我偷了辆车  怎么了
So I stole a fucking car!
见鬼  维戈
Fuck, Viggo!
-老天  维戈  -你不许走
- Christ, Viggo. - You stay!
激怒我的不是你做了什么  儿子
It's not what you did, son, that angers me so.
而是你对谁做的
It's who you did it to.
谁  那个无名小卒
Who? That fucking nobody?
那个"无名小卒"
That "fuckin' nobody"...
是约翰·威克
is John Wick.
他曾是我们中的一员
He once was an associate of ours.
他们叫他雅佳婆婆
They call him Baba Yaga.
俄罗斯童话中的邪恶女巫
他是夜魔
The boogeyman?
准确来说  约翰不是夜魔
Well, John wasn't exactly the boogeyman.
他是你派去杀夜魔的人
He was the one you sent to kill the fucking boogeyman.
约翰是一个非常专注
John is a man of focus...
非常投入
commitment...
不达目的不罢休的人
sheer will.
与你完全不同
Something you know very little about.
我曾见过他在一家酒吧里杀了三个人
I once saw him kill three men in a bar...
用一支铅笔
with a pencil.
用一支该死的
With a fuckin'...
铅笔
pencil.
然后某天他突然请求退出
Then suddenly one day he asked to leave.
当然是为了一个女人
It's over a woman, of course.
所以我和他做了个交易
So I made a deal with him.
我给了他一个不可能完成的任务
I gave him an impossible task.
没人能完成的任务
A job no one could have pulled off.
那天他埋葬的尸体
The bodies he buried that day...
奠定了我们今日的基础
laid the foundation of what we are now.
然后  我的儿子
And then, my son...
在他妻子逝世几天后
a few days after his wife died...
偷了他的车
you steal his car...
还杀了他的狗
and kill his fuckin' dog.
父亲  我能解决这件事
Father, I can make this right.
你有什么打算
How do you plan that?
了结我没做完的事
By finishing what I started.
我说的话他都没听进去吗
Did he hear a fucking word I said?
爸爸  我可以做到的  拜托
约索夫  约索夫  听着
Iosef, Iosef, listen.
约翰会来追杀你
John will come for you.
而你什么都不能做
And you will do nothing...
因为你无能为力
because you can do nothing.
所以滚出我的视线
So get the fuck out of my sight.
你好  约翰
Hello, John.
你妻子的事我听说了  我深表遗憾
I heard about your wife, and I'm sorry.
请节哀
My condolences.
看来是命运抑或巧合
It seems to be fate, or happenstance...
又或者只是时运不济
or just bad fuckin' luck
才让我们的道路再度交汇
caused our paths to cross once again.
约翰
John?
我们不要屈从于低级的本能
Let us not resort to our baser instincts...
像个文明人一样处理这件事
and handle this like civilized men...
握手言和...
to move on--
他说什么了
What'd he say?
意思很清楚
Enough.
天哪
Oh, God.
召集人手
Task a crew.
要多少人
H-How many?
你有多少人
How many do you have?
勇者天佑
[拉丁语]
快快睡着  否则 夜魔 上门找
他会从沼泽中来
带走不听话的小孩
夜魔
雅佳婆婆
Baba Yaga.
晚上好  约翰
Evenin', John.
晚上好  吉米
Evenin', Jimmy.
噪音投诉
Noise complaint?
Noise complaint.
你重操旧业了
You, workin' again?
没有  只是处理些事情
No, just sortin' some stuff out.
好吧
Well...
那我就不打扰了
I'll leave you be then.
-晚安  约翰  -晚安  吉米
- Good night, John. - Good night, Jimmy.
我是威克
This is Wick.
对  约翰·威克  是我没错
Yes, John Wick. That's right.
我想预订十二人的晚餐
I'd like to make a dinner reservation for 12.
很高兴见到你  约翰
Good to see you, John.
查理
Charlie.
专业废物处理
你气色不错
You look good.
我还担心你把这一切都抛诸脑后了呢
And here I'd feared you'd left all this behind.
近期你还会联系我吗
Will I be hearin' from you anytime soon?
再见  查理
Good bye, Charlie.
约翰
John.
他当然会这么做
Of course he did.
悬赏约翰·威克的人头
Put a contract on John Wick.
赏金多少
How much?
两百万
Two million.
舍不得孩子套不着 狼
维戈  说英语好吗
English, Viggo, please.
让约索夫待在红圈  等他来
Put losef in the Red Circle and wait.
等谁
For what?
当然是等约翰·威克
For John Wick, of course.
谢谢
Thank you.
什么风把你给吹来了
To what do I owe this visit?
有个活要找你做
I have a job for you.
你可以打电话
And I've got a phone.
我想当面和你说
I want to offer you this face to face...
因为你可能不愿接受
seeing as how you might find it personal.
你愿意为两百万干掉约翰·威克吗
Would you kill John Wick for two million dollars?
毕竟  你们很要好
After all, you were close.
悬赏只有我知道吗
Is the contract exclusive?
不  是公开的
No, it's open.
情况紧急  必须速战速决
It's a timely matter. It has to be handled quickly.
这活我接了
Consider it done.
谢谢你  马库斯  我就知道我能信任你
Thank you, Marcus. I know I can trust you.
谢谢你的饮料
Thanks for the drink.
♪ This world doesn't need no opera ♪
Killing Strangers - Marilyn Manson
♪ We're here for the operation ♪
♪ We don't need ♪
♪ A bigger knife, yeah ♪
♪ 'Cause they got guns ♪
♪ We got guns ♪
♪ They got guns ♪
♪ We got guns, you better run ♪
♪ You better run ♪
♪ You better run, you better run ♪
♪ We're killing strangers ♪
♪ So we don't kill ♪
♪ The ones that we love ♪
♪ We're killing strangers ♪
♪ So we don't kill ♪
♪ The ones that we love ♪
918房间  希望你入住愉快
Room 918. Do enjoy your stay.
谢谢
Thanks.
很高兴又见到你  约翰
Good seeing you again, John.
珀金斯
Perkins.
你预订了两晚
I have you for two nights.
看情况  也许会多待几天
Depending on business, it may be more.
好的  先生
Of course, sir.
这地方什么时候重新装修的
So when did the old place get a face lift?
大约四年前
Around four years ago.
不过我向你保证  先生
But I assure you, sir...
这里并没有什么变化
she really hasn't changed much.
-没换老板  -没换老板
- Same owner? - Same owner.
818房间
Room 818.
一如既往
And, as always...
很荣幸
it is a pleasure...
又能接待你  威克先生
having you with us again, Mr. Wick.
你在干什么  约翰
What are you doing, John?
看你
Looking at you.
过来
Come here.
♪ 你好  宝贝 ♪
♪ Hello, baby ♪
Evil Man Blues - The Candy Shop Boys
♪ 我看到你和我 ♪
♪ I see you and l ♪
你好  温斯顿
Hello, Winston.
乔纳森
Jonathan.
据我所知
Now, as I recall...
一向只有你打别人  而不是被别人打
weren't you the one tasked to dole out the beatings,
不是吗
not receive them?
看来我生疏了
Rusty, I guess.
什么风把你吹来了
To what do we owe the pleasure?
约索夫·塔拉索夫
Iosef Tarasov.
-他怎么了  -我想跟他聊聊
- What about him? - I'd like to talk with him.
你说聊聊
A talk, you say.
这说法我再熟悉不过了  乔纳森
I'm familiar with the parlance, Jonathan.
我要先问问你
I want to ask you this.
你回归了吗
Have you returned to the fold?
只是路过
Just visiting.
你有考虑清楚吗
Have you thought this through?
里里外外考虑清楚
I mean, chewed down to the bone?
你成功退出了
You got out once.
这次哪怕你只踏入一个脚尖
You dip so much as a pinky back into this pond...
也许就会被再次
you may well find something reaches out...
拖进这趟浑水里
and drags you back into its depths.
他在什么地方
Where do I find him?
威克在大陆酒店
Wick's at the Continental.
欢迎回家  约翰
Welcome home, John.
那里有个熟人愿意帮我们干掉他
We have a contact there who's willing to take him out for us.
是吗
Yeah?
真是胆大包天
How brazen.
如果这个人愿意打破大陆酒店的规矩
If they're willing to break the rules of Continental,
赏金加倍
double the bounty.
你知道规矩
You know the rules.
酒店内部不得干活
No business can be conducted on these premises...
以免招致重罚
lest incurring heavy penalties.
喝一杯
Have a drink...
放轻松
and relax...
只是暂时的
for now.
是私人恩怨
It's personal.
♪ 早餐吃鱼子酱  每晚喝香槟酒 ♪
♪ I want caviar for breakfast and champagne every night ♪
天啊  乔纳森
Holy shit. Jonathan.
-艾蒂  -天啊
- Hey, Addy. - My God!
有多久没见了  四年了吧
How long has it been? Four years?
五年多吧
Five and change.
跟我说说  另一种生活滋味如何
So tell me, how was life on the other side?
非常好  艾蒂
It was good, Addy.
远远超出我应得的
Far better than I deserved.
-很遗憾听闻你的...  -谢谢
- Hey, I'm sorry to hear about your-- - Thanks.
我从没见过你这个样子
I've never seen you like this.
什么样子
Like what?
脆弱的样子
Vulnerable.
我退休了
I'm retired.
如果你来这里喝酒  说明你没退休
Not if you're drinkin' here, you're not.
-和平时一样吗  -谢谢
- Usual? - Please.
♪ 但我会令你倾家荡产 ♪
♪ But I'll empty your pockets ♪
♪ 让你留在痛苦之中 ♪
♪ Leave you in misery ♪
本店的一点小心意
Compliments of the house.
♪ 但我会令你倾家荡产 ♪
♪ But I'll empty your pockets ♪
谢谢
Thanks.
♪ 让你留在痛苦之中 ♪
♪ Leave you in misery ♪
红圈
二楼  汇报情况
贵宾室安全
楼厅  汇报情况
没有看到他
地下室  汇报情况
地下室安全
出口
看到那妞的胸了吗
Did you see the tits on that girl?
希望莉塔今晚上班
I hope Lita is working tonight.
兄弟  下来跟我们喝一杯
我负责保护一个小鬼  不负责照看醉鬼
你怕那个该死的夜魔吗
Are you scared of the fuckin' boogeyman?
-我可不怕  -不怕吗
- I'm not. - No?
但是你应该怕
But you should be.
再拿一瓶来
I want another bottle!
快他妈去拿  再给我拿一瓶
Right fuckin' now! Go get me a bottle!
快点
Come on!
你好  弗朗西斯
Hello, Francis.
威克先生
Mr. Wick.
你减重了
减了超过
27公斤
是吗
真厉害
你是来干活的吗  先生
Are you here on business, sir?
恐怕是的  弗朗西斯
Afraid so, Francis.
不如你休息一晚吧
Why don't you take the night off.
谢谢你  先生
Thank you, sir.
约索夫 在哪儿
去你的  王八蛋
Fuck you, motherfucker.
约索夫在哪儿
Where is Iosef?
在楼下澡堂
Bathhouse, downstairs.
你偷了我的车.
还杀了我的狗
去你的
看到约翰·威克了吗
没有
二楼  汇报情况
地下室  一切安全吗
安全
他来了
快走
Go!
跟我来
威克来了
他在楼里
让开  他来了  他来了
Move! He's here! He's fucking here!
在后面  他追过来了
He's there! He's coming!
上车  上车
Get in! Get in!
快点  快
Come on! Come on!
维克托  你他妈在哪儿
维克托死了.
万事皆有代价
晚上好  威克先生
Good evening, Mr. Wick.
晚上好
Good evening.
有什么能为你效劳的吗
How may I be of service?
医生在吗
Is the doctor in?
全年无休  先生
Yes, sir. 24/7.
-请他去我的房间  -好的  先生
- Send him up, please. - Yes, sir.
你们的洗衣服务怎么样
How good's your laundry?
很遗憾  没人能挽救你的衣服
I'm sorry to say that no one's that good.
嗯  我想也是
No. I thought not.
我建议你喝一杯  先生
May I suggest a drink, sir.
波旁威士忌如何
Bourbon, perhaps.
听起来很不错
That sounds perfect.
我的行动能力会受到怎样的影响
So what sort of movement am I looking at?
如果你想要伤口愈合
Well, if you're lookin' to heal...
那就尽量限制行动
then keep it marginal.
但是  如果你还有...
However, if you still have...
未尽之事
business to attend to...
行动之前先吃两片
take two of these beforehand.
伤口会裂开  你会流血
Your stitches'll tear and you'll bleed...
但是行动完全不受影响
but you'll have full function.
你需要止痛药吗
Do you need anything for the pain?
不用  有酒就行了
No, I've got that covered.
约翰
Hey, John.
-珀金斯  -我擅自进来了
- Perkins? - I thought I'd let myself in.
我发现了
I noticed.
我还以为至少要三枚金币才请得动珀金斯女士
I never knew Ms. Perkins to get out of bed for less than three.
打破酒店的规矩  维戈要给我四枚金币
Viggo's giving me four to break hotel rules.
我向你保证  这样做很不明智
That's unwise, I assure you.
你打架一直像个娘们
You were always a pussy.
喂
Yes?
很抱歉这么晚打电话给你
I apologize for calling you at this hour...
但我们接到了很多来自你楼层的
but we have received a number of grievances from your floor...
噪音投诉
concerning the noise.
很抱歉
My apologies.
我刚才在接待一位不速之客
I was dealing with an uninvited guest.
你是否需要...
Have you need then of, say...
预订晚餐呢
a dinner reservation, perhaps?
也许  我之后再联系你
Perhaps. I'll have to get back to you.
不
No!
约索夫在哪儿
Where's Iosef?
去死吧
Fuck you.
-维戈在哪儿  -我什么也不会告诉你
- Where's Viggo? - I'm not telling you shit!
你真想死在这里吗  珀金斯
Do you really wanna die here, Perkins?
给我点情报
Give me somethin'.
小俄罗斯
Little Russia.
坎农法院附近有个教堂
There's a church near Cannon Court.
-教堂怎么了  -那是个幌子
- What about it? - It's a front.
维戈的私货都藏在那里
It's where Viggo keeps his private stash.
谢谢
Thank you.
我认识你吗
Do I know you?
应该吧
I'm thinkin' so.
约翰
Hey, John.
哈利
Hey, Harry.
没事吧
Everything all right?
嗯  没事
Yeah. Everything's fine.
-那我就不打扰你了  -哈利
- I'll leave you to it then. - Hey, Harry.
想赚一枚金币吗  盯着这个睡美人
You keen on earning a coin? Babysittin' the sleepin' one?
-捕捉并释放  -捕捉并释放
- Catch and release? - Catch and release.
孩子  需要帮助吗
My son, how might I help you?
王八蛋
Motherfucker!
你知道你惹的是什么人吗?
嗯.
我知道
我们去保险库
Let's go to the vault.
开门
Open it.
你以为你能恐吓我开门吗?
没错开门.
维戈会杀了我的
Viggo will kill me.
女士们  出去
Ladies, out.
祝你们愉快
老实说  你准备拿这些东西干什么
Honestly, what do you think you're going to do with all of that?
干这个
This.
带那个蠢货 来见我
别担心
Don't worry.
保洁员会发现你的
Housekeeping will find you.
你一向这样对待淑女吗
Treat all your ladies like this?
你可不是淑女  相信我
You are no lady. Trust me.
你叫哈利  对吧
Harry, is it?
你想赚比一枚金币更多的钱吗
How would you like to earn more than just a gold coin?
你打破了规矩
You've broken the rules.
你在大陆酒店内干活了
You've done business on Continental grounds.
管理层不会轻易容忍
And management does not take kindly...
这种行为
to that sort of behavior.
去他的管理层
Fuck management.
别担心  保洁员会发现你的
Don't worry. Housekeeping'll find you.
该死 ！
尘归尘  土归土
Ashes to ashes.
我们能重振旗鼓吗
Can we recover from this?
维戈  你知道那个保险库里放了什么吧
Viggo, you know what was in that vault, right?
该死
Shit.
上啊
Come on!
掩护我!
这么说吧  约翰
I'll say this, John.
你确实打破了他们的常规
They sure as fuck broke the mold with you.
知道吗  你总是
You always had a certain...
那么大胆
audacity about you, you know.
嗯
Yeah.
我可以说你仍然是以前的约翰·威克
I can say you're still very much the John Wick of old.
是吗
Am I?
人是不会变的  你心知肚明
People don't change. You know that.
时代会改变
Times, they do.
你知道那个保险库里放了什么吗
Do you know what was in that vault?
艺术品和现金  确实有一定价值
Artwork, cash, not without its worth.
但是我在这座城市里掌握的把柄
But the leverage I had on this city--
录音  物证  勒索
audio recordings, physical evidence, blackmail--
都是无价之宝
it was fuckin' priceless!
无价之宝
Priceless!
嗯  烧掉那些我还挺享受的
Yeah. I kind of enjoyed that.
是啊
Yeah.
是啊  我知道你挺享受的
Yeah, I know you did. Yeah.
你是在笑吗
Are you really laughing?
那么
So--
后来你结婚了  是吗  安定下来了
then you got married, huh? Settled down.
你是怎么做到的
How did you manage that anyways?
大概是走运吧
Luck, l guess.
嗯
Yeah.
你有了妻子  我有了儿子
Yeah, while you had your wife, I had my son.
相信我  你的命比我好多了
And believe me, you had a far better deal.
然后你离开了
And then you left.
你退出的方式
And the way you got out...
自欺欺人地告诉自己  过去不能左右将来
lying to yourself that the past held no sway over the future.
但是最终
But in the end...
我们中很多人的罪行都得到了回报
a lot of us are rewarded for our misdeeds...
所以上帝带走了你妻子
which is why God took your wife...
并且让我面对你的愤怒
and unleashed you upon me.
这种生活
This life...
如影随形
follows you.
抓住你不放
It clings to you...
感染每一个接近你的人
infecting everyone who comes close to you.
我们被诅咒了  你和我
We are cursed, you and I.
这一点上我们意见一致
On that we agree.
终于找到共同点了
Finally, common ground.
好
Okay.
收手
Step aside.
把你儿子给我
Give me your son.
约翰·威克
John Wick.
夜魔
只是一辆破车  只是一条臭狗
It was just a fucking car. Just a fuckin' dog.
只是一条狗
Just a dog.
维戈
Viggo.
怎么了
Yeah?
海伦去世后  我失去了一切
When Helen died, I lost everything.
直到那条狗来到我门前
Until that dog arrived on my doorstep--
我妻子最后的礼物
a final gift from my wife.
那一刻  我仿佛感受到了一丝希望
In that moment, I received some semblance of hope...
一个不用独自哀悼的机会
an opportunity to grieve unalone.
然后你儿子
And your son...
把它夺走了
took that from me.
-天啊  -把它偷走了
- Oh, God. - Stole that from me.
把它杀死了
Killed that from me!
人们总是在问我是否回来了
People keep asking if I'm back...
我一直没找到答案
and I haven't really had an answer.
但是现在  对  我觉得我回来了
But now, yeah, I'm thinkin' I'm back.
所以要么你交出你儿子
So you can either hand over your son.
要么就和他一起惨叫着死去
Or you can die screaming alongside him!
冷静点  冷静点
Cool it. Cool it.
约翰
John!
-老天  -他在哪儿
- Jesus. - Where is he?
见鬼
Shit!
那你向我保证  如果我告诉你他在哪儿
I have your word then, if I tell you where he is,
你就放我走
that you'll let me walk away?
取消悬赏
Pull the contract.
成交
Done.
他在一处安全屋  在布鲁克林
He's kept in a safe house. Brooklyn.
华莱士广场434号
434 Wallace Place.
-他们知道你要去  -当然
- They know you're coming. - Of course.
但是无关紧要
But it won't matter.
三号
报到
到.
全员待命
Who You Talkin' to Man? - Nostalghia
♪ A pretty beggar on my knees ♪
♪ What's that 'cross your eyelid ♪
♪ What's that across your tongue ♪
二号
报到.
到.
♪ And I wanna know ♪
♪ Who you talkin' to, man ♪
你能不能别玩那该死的电子游戏了
Will you stop playing the fucking video game?
二号.
到.
三号.
报到.
到.
你能不能别玩那该死的电子游戏了
Will you stop playing the fucking video game?
蹲下  蹲下
Get down! Get down!
快点  快点  蹲下  蹲下
Come on! Come on! Get down! Get down!
♪ How do you like me now ♪
♪ Hey, hey, hey ♪
只是一条臭...
♪ Who you talkin' to, man ♪
作出安排
Make the arrangements.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是我们的荣幸  先生
Our pleasure, sir.
来自管理层的离别礼物
A parting gift. From the management.
补偿昨晚的不幸...
Compensation for last night's unfortunate...
事件
incident.
我还要救你的小命多少次
How many times do I have to save your ass?
-非常感谢  -别客气
- I appreciate it. - Of course.
你看起来糟透了
You look terrible.
不  我看起来退休了
No, I look retired.
退休了
Retired?
你真的相信吗
You really believe that?
你创造了新的生活
You made a new life.
你会找到回去的路的
You'll find your way back to it.
该回家了
It's time to go home.
赶紧开始吧  不管这是要干什么
Let's get on with this, whatever the fuck this is.
你好  马库斯
Hello, Marcus.
我是约翰
This is John.
非常感谢你让我儿子死得很痛快
I appreciate you granting my son a swift death.
这话我也不知道该怎么接
I wouldn't know how to reply to that either.
马库斯背叛了我
Marcus betrayed me.
你取消了悬赏
You pulled the contract.
没取消之前  你有的是机会
And while it was open, you had every chance...
有的是杀约翰·威克的机会
every opportunity to kill John Wick.
如果你完成了你的工作
And if you had done your job...
我儿子就不会死了
my son would be still alive!
这样一来
And in so doing...
他就违反了基本原则
he broke the cardinal rule.
谢谢
Thank you.
珀金斯女士
Ms. Perkins.
我怎么毫不惊讶呢
Why am I not surprised?
一不做  二不休
In for a penny, in for a pound.
所以约翰  我别无选择
So, John, I had no choice.
我一直很喜欢你  马库斯
I always liked you, Marcus.
最后一个保守派
The last of the old guard.
但是和其他人不同  你怎么死我说了算
But unlike the others, you go out on my terms.
不  不
No! No!
不  好先生
No, my good sir.
我怎么死我说了算
I go out on my own.
Killing Strangers - Marilyn Manson
♪ We're killing strangers ♪
♪ So we don't kill ♪
♪ The ones that we love ♪
♪ Love ♪
看吧
See?
♪ Love ♪
♪ You better run ♪
算你狠  老朋友
Well played, old friend.
♪ We got guns ♪
♪ We got guns ♪?
-完事了吗  维戈  -完事了
- We done, Viggo? - We're done.
好  给你
Okay. Here.
谢谢
Thank you.
喂  给直升机加油
Yeah. Fuel the chopper.
珀金斯女士  很抱歉这么晚打电话给你
Ms. Perkins, I apologize for calling you at this hour.
珀金斯女士
Ms. Perkins.
你在大陆酒店的会员资格被
Your membership to the Continental has been...
你自作自受  取消了
by thine own hand, revoked.
我知道你在想什么  乔纳森
I know what you're thinking, Jonathan.
我们有自己的原则
We live by a code.
所以这不是我告诉你的  但是
Which is why I'm not the one telling you that...
某个停机坪上的某架直升机
a certain helicopter at a certain helipad...
正在加油准备接某人
is being fueled for a certain someone.
-你拿我的烟了吗  -我拿你的烟了
- Have you got my cigarettes? - Yeah, I got your cigarettes.
我们后面的是谁
操
Fuck!
真好  开快点
Yeah. Super. Let's go. Faster!
直升机就在那边  快点
The helicopter's right down there. Come on! Let's go!
该死的  我就知道他会来
Shit! Goddamn, I knew he'd come.
这家伙有什么毛病
What's fuckin' wrong with this guy?
谁给我把枪  谁有枪
Somebody give me a gun. Who's got a gun?
天啊  我的头
Oh, God! My fucking head.
-这一下真厉害  -谁有枪
- That was a good one. - Who's got a gun?
去杀了他
操
Fuck!
直升机就在那边  我们必须过去
The helicopter's right over there. We have to get over there.
天啊  我需要枪
Oh, my God, I need a gun.
说英语好吗
English, please.
祝你好运
Good luck.
俄罗斯混蛋
Russian cocksucker.
操
Fuck!
不
No!
别用枪了  约翰
No more guns, John.
别用子弹了
No more bullets.
只剩你和我了  约翰
Just you and me, John.
你和我
You and me.
到底怎么了  约翰
What happened, John?
我们是专业人士  文明人
We were professionals. Civilized.
你觉得我看起来文明吗
Do I look civilized to you?
再会  约翰
Be seeing you, John.
嗯
Yeah.
再会
Be seeing you.
来吧  约翰  我们回家
Come on, John. Let's go home.
没事了
It's okay.
我们回家
Let's go home.